《指定幸存者》前情提要
Previously on "Designated Survivor"...
美国最喜爱的副总统人选
America's favorite vice presidential candidate
和中情局头号通缉的雇佣兵
and the CIA's most wanted mercenary
相互认识
know each other.
我找到了能够
I'm working a lead
把彼得·麦克利什拉下台的证据
that could prove damning to Peter MacLeish.
霍斯拉滕议员
Congresswoman Hookstraten
刚刚打来电话要求延期
just called for an extended recess.
她要推迟麦克利什的听证会
She's delaying MacLeish's hearing.
政府中有人把
Someone inside the U.S. Government
蓝图交给了马吉德·纳萨尔
handed over the blueprints to Majid Nassar
导致了国会被炸
for the Capitol bombing.
我们中间出了个叛徒
There's a traitor among us.
汉娜·威尔士特别探员
Special Agent Hannah Wells
她的注意力总是在我身上
seemed to be a bit obsessed with me.
我只是希望她不会试着用阴谋论
I just hope she isn't trying to convince the speaker
来说服议长
of any conspiracy theory.
我找到了证据
I found the evidence I was looking for.
我到了后会解释一切的
I'll explain everything when I get there.
我的天啊  你还好吗
My God, are you okay?
能听到我讲话吗
Can you hear me?
你遇到了车祸
Look, you've been in an accident,
但是救援马上就到
but help is on the way.
机密文件
坐稳别动  好吗
Just try and sit still, okay?
别动脖子
And don't move your neck.
你会没事的
You're gonna be fine.
议长女士  我知道你在等人
Madam Speaker, I know you're waiting for someone,
但整个国家都在等我们
but the entire country is waiting for us.
投票不能再拖延了
We can't delay this vote any longer.
彼得·麦克利什是英雄
Peter MacLeish is a hero.
我的线人声称
Who my witness claims
有把彼得·麦克利什拉下台的证据
to have damning evidence against.
不找出来是什么
We owe it to our constituents
就对不起我们的选民
to find out what that is.
该死 快接电话
Damn it. Pick up.
是我
It's me.
我跟丢了
I lost her.
汤姆  这是什么
Tom, what is this?
一份蓝图
It's a blueprint.
A blueprint?
一份如何炸掉国会大厦的指南
A guide for how to blow up the Capitol building.
-从哪儿来的  -政府内部
- Where did it come from? - Us.
国防部
The Department of Defense.
显然在911之后
Apparently after 9/11,
五角大楼针对所有重要政府建筑
the Pentagon did a threat assessment
都做了威胁评估
on all key government buildings
用以弄清薄弱环节
to show us - where our weaknesses were.
那你在想什么
A-And so you're thinking what?
我觉得政府内部有人
I think someone inside our government
把蓝图给了艾尔萨卡  用来炸毁国会
gave that blueprint to Al-Sakar to blow up the Capitol.
还有谁知道这个
Who else knows about this?
只有你和迈克
Just you and Mike.
汤姆  你得通知国安部
Tom, you need to call in someone
或者联调局的人
from Homeland Security or the FBI.
不  在弄清楚这是什么之前
No, no, we can't call anyone
不能通知任何人
until we know exactly what this is.
你现在吓到我了
You're scaring me right now.
你还记得搬来第一晚
You remember the first night
在玫瑰园的时候
we were here in the Rose Garden?
你问我是否觉得我们是目标
You asked me - if I thought we were a target.
我说我不知道
I said I didn't know.
但是现在...
But now...
我认为在确定安全之前
...I think you need to take the kids
你得把孩子们带走
and leave until we know it's safe.
带他们去哪儿
Take them where?
哪里安全呢
Where's "Safe"?
-不知道  -这正是我要说的
- I don't know. - But that's my point.
如果我们都不知道是谁在追  那要怎么逃
How do we run if we don't know who we're running from?
迈克正在带
Mike's bringing in
这份文件的起草者恩莱特博士过来
the man who wrote the file, Dr. Enright.
也许他给我们一些答案
Maybe he's got some answers for us.
但在找到答案之前
But until then,
我们不能相信任何人
we cannot trust anyone.
到此为止
Okay, time's up.
如果你不迅速进来开会
If you don't join us inside immediately,
我会告诉公众
I will tell the public
你为了自己上位当总统
that you blocked Peter MacLeish's appointment
一再阻碍彼得·麦克利什就职
so you would be next in line for the presidency.
召集议员开会
Reconvene the committee.
汉娜
Hannah?!
-你怎么了  -别让人找到我
- What happened? - You can't let them find me.
天啊  你在流血
Oh, my God, you're bleeding!
你需要治疗
You need help!
恰克  别打电话
Chuck, you can't call anyone.
我得带你去医院
I have to get you to the hospital.
你需要看医生
You need a-a doctor.
你...汉娜
You -- Hannah?
汉娜
Hannah!
指定幸存者
第一季 第十集
副总统候选人彼得·麦克利什
众议院司法委员会
Now that the House Judiciary Committee
已经通过了提名
has given the nominee the green light,
全院议员将在深夜进行投票
the full House will convene for a late-night vote
许多人猜测彼得·麦克利什
that many expect will make Peter MacLeish
翻译： sienna  长颈鹿  桃子  幸存薇薇安
■
将会成为美国下一任副总统
the next Vice President of the United States.
恭喜
Congratulations.
翻译：murky  胖胖胖  Michael  幸存薇薇安
敬彼得·麦克利什
To Peter MacLeish.
-敬新的副总统  -干了
- To the new Vice President. - Hear, hear.
校对：小早
怎么了  喝啤酒度假呢
What's up, Spring Break?
得了吧
Oh, come on.
时间轴：   姜姜   壬虚浪影   格瑞特
如果你得应付六十个如狼似虎的记者
You know, if you had 60 news-hungry journalists
整天嚷嚷着要拿到纳萨尔被杀一案的消息
clamoring for information about Nassar's murder,
你也会口渴的
you'd be thirsty, too.
后期：虫虫不咬人    总监：小早
也许麦克利什的当选消息
Maybe the MacLeish confirmation will keep them
-能让他们翻篇了  -是啊
- off your back for a news cycle. - Yeah.
唯一能让我远离他们烦扰的是真相
The only thing that's gonna keep them off my back is an answer,
-然而我们目前没有  -的确
- which, as I remind you, we don't have. - Yeah.
有传言说麦克利什带了一批
Rumor is MacLeish is bringing
自己的工作人员进驻白宫
a bunch of his House staffers with him.
你们有认识的吗
You guys know any of them?
有  以前每周二晚我都会
Yeah, I used to play soccer every Tuesday night
和他的网络主管踢足球
with his Coms director.
那家伙超无趣的
That guy's sharp as a marble.
我曾和他的法案助理在杜威海滩
I once shared a summer house in Dewey Beach
同住一间避暑别墅
with his legislative assistants.
虽然当时才19岁  但他们看起来都很厉害
I mean, we were only 19, but they seemed on top of it.
-19岁吗  -对  我得灌很多酒
- 19? - Yes, and I will need plenty more of these
才会和你说当时的故事
before you get any of those stories.
好了  我得去新街见一下演讲撰稿人了
All right, I'm gonna go meet the speech writers on New Street.
你们也可以跟着来
You guys are welcomto join.
不了  我们在这挺好的  赛斯  谢谢你
Nah, we're good where we are, Seth. Thank you.
好吧  明天见
All right. See you tomorrow.
-晚安  -路上小心
- Have a good night. - Get home safe.
他的妻子贝丝和两个女儿
...will be his wife, Beth, and their two daughters.
副总统候选人彼得·麦克利什
你能相信现在所发生的一切吗
Can you believe everything that's happened?
局势跌宕起伏
It's been a roller coaster, for sure.
我不得不承认  刚来这的时候
You know, I have to admit, when I first got here,
我以为你会不择一切手段
I thought that you were gonna do everything you could
将我赶出白宫
to get me out of the White House,
但全靠你  我现在才能留在这
not be the reason I'm still here.
我也必须承认  你刚来的时候
Well, I have to admit, when you first got here,
我觉得你无法处理好这一切
I didn't think you could handle it.
是啊  你说我是菜鸟
Yeah, you called me a minor leaguer.
但我错了
Yeah, well, I was wrong.
甚至可以说  我是在向你学习
If anything, I'm learning from you.
总统先生  阿兰·恩莱特博士到了
Mr. President, Dr. Alan Enright.
恩莱特博士  请坐
Dr. Enright, please.
我需要你核实一下这是不是你做的
I need you to verify for me that this is your work.
你肯定知道是我没错
I think you know that it is.
这应该就是把我带来这的原因吧  总统先生
I think that's why I'm here, Mr. President,
但我与国会爆炸案无关
but I had nothing to do with what happened at the Capitol.
我写这份文件是为了防止其发生
I wrote this file to prevent what happened,
而非制造爆炸
not to cause it.
就算这是真话  你也必须承认
Even if that's true, you had to realize
有人利用了你的工作成果
that someone used your work
策划并实施了爆炸案
to plan and carry out the bombing.
他们全按图纸实施爆炸
They followed it to the letter.
你之前为什么不上报
Why didn't you come forward?
我闭上眼就能看到大厦崩塌
I close my eyes. I can see the building fall.
铁筋熔化  大理石被炸得粉碎
The cast iron melting, the marble crumble.
无论谁是真凶
Whoever did this,
这都是一个空前巨大的阴谋
we're talking about a conspiracy of unparalleled proportions.
我吓坏了  总统先生
I was scared, Mr. President.
好吧
Okay.
博士  我需要你告诉我每一个
Doctor, I'm gonna need you to give me
可以看到这份文件的人的名字
every single name that had access to this file.
品牌广告推广合作  普罗米修斯  plmxs2016@gmail.com
我给这份文件加了源控制加密
I put an ORCON classification on this file,
意味着能看到文件的人数是有限的
which means the number of people who saw it is limited.
然后就发给国防部安保部门了
And then I sent it to the DOD security team.
他们全都死于国会爆炸案
They all died in the Capitol.
我还发给了北方司令部负责人
I also sent it to the head of NORCOM.
品牌广告推广合作  普罗米修斯  plmxs2016@gmail.com
给了格莱迪将军吗
You sent the file to General Grady?
我写这份文件时是两年零六个月前
I wrote this file two years and six months ago.
那时格莱迪将军还不是北方司令部的负责人
General Grady was not the head of NORCOM then.
那是谁
Who was?
被你撤职的那位将军
The general you fired.
哈里斯·科克兰
Harris Cochrane.
麦克利什及众议院司法委员会...
...that MacLeish probably with the House Judiciary Committee.
彼得·麦克利什被称为"联邦政府的奇迹"
Peter MacLeish has been named the Miracle on the Potomac,
他重返国会将可能重新定义
and this return to the capital will hopefully redefine
公众关系
the public's association with...
昨晚的历史性投票结果为
With a final tally of 424-9,
424票赞成  9票反对
Congressman MacLeish
众议院司法委员会
was confirmed by the House of Representatives
正式确认麦克利什议员当选副总统
in a historic vote late last night.
与此同时   组织者正在加班加点准备
Meanwhile, organizers are working double time to prepare for...
你没事吧  现在感觉如何
You okay? How you feeling?
好多了  谢谢你
Better. Yeah, thanks to you.
慢着点
Easy.
-恰克  你缝合了我的伤口吗  -是啊
- Hey, Chuck. Did you glue my wound? - Yeah.
-你在哪儿学的  -油管
- Where did you learn to do that? - YouTube.
白宫方面确认了
House confirmed him.
他将在下午宣誓就职
They're swearing him in this afternoon.
彼得·麦克利什的当选
Peter MacLeish's confirmation
麦克利什当选副总统
几乎没有受到任何新任白宫成员的反对
received no opposition from the newly appointed...
无论是谁确保了麦克利什的生还
Whoever made sure MacLeish survived
并令其当选副总统  肯定是有目的的
wanted him as VP for a reason,
我们还剩不到八小时来制止这件事了
so we have less than eight hours to make sure that doesn't happen.
听着
Okay, look,
我知道你并不想听这些
I know this isn't - what you're gonna want to hear,
但...
but...
有人要杀你
...someone tried to kill you,
亚特伍德身陷囹圄
Atwood's in prison,
法索停了我的职
Foerstel has me on suspension.
-也许我们是时候...  -什么
- Maybe it's time we -- - What?
-放弃  -汉娜
- Quit? - Hannah.
你昨晚差点死了
You almost died last night.
我满手都是你的血
I literally had to scrub your blood off of my hands.
他们还要对我们做什么
What else do they need to do to us?
恰克  你为什么加入联调局
Chuck, why did you join the FBI?
为了帮助人们
To help people.
我是为了激怒我父亲
I joined to piss my father off.
他是芝加哥的顶级外科医生
He's a top surgeon in Chicago,
他希望我继承他的衣钵
and he wanted me - to follow in his footsteps.
他拿枪指着我
Practically held me at gunpoint
送我去约翰霍普金斯医学院
and took me to Johns Hopkins.
我去了
So I went.
研究生读到一半
And, uh, -- halfway through grad school,
我逃跑了  跳上一辆火车
I walked out, jumped on a train,
来到了华盛顿  申请加入了联调局
went to D.C., -- and signed up for the FBI.
我也想帮助别人
I wanted to help, too.
但要以我自己的方式
I just wanted to do it in my own way.
犯罪分子不会停止
It's not their job to stop.
阻止他们是我们的职责
It's our job to stop them.
我也很害怕
And I'm scared, too.
但如果我们放弃  而他们胜利了
But if we quit, they win, and then...
那天失去亲人的所有人
everyone who lost someone that day...
都将永无安宁之日
they'll never know peace.
想得美
Nice try.
你的词典里从来没有害怕两个字
You've never been scared in your life.
好吧  我加入
Fine. I'm in.
下一步做什么
What's the next step?
-与霍斯拉滕议员取得联系吗  -不
- Get back in touch with Hookstraten? - No.
我告诉她我有指控麦克利什的证据
I told her I had evidence on MacLeish,
-马上有人来杀我  -好吧
- and someone tries to kill me. - Right.
他们拿走了全部证据
And they took all my evidence.
打匿名电话的那个女人提供的所有证据都没了
The evidence I got from the woman who's been calling me.
不  我告诉过你
No, I already told you
我没办法再次追踪她的电话
I can't trace the call from her again,
即使我能做到  我也被停职了
and even if I could, I'm shut out of my office.
你最好另辟蹊径
Then you'd better get creative
因为这是我们唯一的线索
'cause it's the only lead we got.
有人看到你带他进来吗
Did anyone see you bring him in?
没有  总统先生
No, sir.
防止他被跟踪
I kept him off Waves
我从东翼带他进来的
and brought him in through the East Wing.
时间还早  所以并没有太大问题
It was still early, so it wasn't a problem.
好的  很好
Okay, good.
谢谢你  迈克
Thank you, Mike.
如此安静不太像这个地方原本的样子
It's different in here when it's quiet.
恰恰相反
On the contrary.
这才是这个房间的常态
This is what this room is usually like.
风平浪静而非狂风暴雨
More calm than storm.
将军  我需要你看看这个
General, I need you to look at this.
迈克
Mike?
这看起来像国会爆炸的重现
This looks like a re-enactment of the Capitol bombing.
不是的
Well, it's not.
将军  这是12-80C号文件
General, this is file 12-80C,
是五角大楼在爆炸发生的两年半以前
a threat assessment created by the Pentagon
所做的威胁评估
2 1/2 years before the bombing.
总统先生  在此之前我从未见过这个
Mr. President, I have never seen this before.
我想未必如此
I find that highly unlikely.
该文件撰写者设置了源控制加密
This file was given an ORCON classification.
看过它的人
I can count on my hand
屈指可数
the number of people that have seen it.
你是名单里唯一一个
Your name is the only one on the list
在爆炸中幸存的人
that survived the bombing.
我收到过这个文件
This was sent to me,
但我并没有机会打开它
but I never had - the opportunity to read it.
这个文件由国防部长重新定级
That file was reclassified by the Secretary of Defense
在我打开前
and recalled electronically from my computer
就已经从我电脑上撤回了
before I could access it.
你指望我会相信
And you expect me to believe
你只记得这些吗
that you just remembered that?
收到一份没来得及看就被国防部长
A file taken from my hand by the Secretary of Defense
撤回的文件吗
at a moment's notice?
一位中将被告知
A Lieutenant General being told
无权阅读某文件这种事吗
he's not cleared to read something?
以前从未发生过  在我身上没有
Never happened before, not to me.
是什么情况
What would be the circumstances
会让国防部长
that would cause the Secretary of Defense
-给一份文件重新定级  -我不知道
- to reclassify a document like that? - I don't know,
但这不是他单方面可以决定的
but it's not something he could do unilaterally.
他一定收到了指令
He must've been given orders.
谁的指令
By who?
指挥领导高低有别
There's a chain of command.
国防部长收到的指令只可能来自一个地方
Only one place the Sec Def gets his orders from.
白宫
The White House.
将军  在证明你所言非虚之前
General, you'll be detained
你将被扣留  -我明白
- until we can verify your story. - I understand.
总统先生
Mr. President.
您遇到大麻烦了
You have a serious problem.
虽然您找我不是要我帮你
And while you may not ask for my help,
若您需要  我愿为您效劳  总统先生
it's here if you want it, sir.
艾米丽
Hey, Emily.
我刚在想  如今麦克利什议员被任命
So, I was thinking, now that MacLeish is confirmed,
我们应该立刻安排听证会
we should start scheduling committee hearings right away
以确定总统内阁人选
to push the president's cabinet nominees through.
好主意
That's a great idea.
找一些跑腿的人开始着手准备
We should get some Leg Affairs folks to start prepping.
我这就安排
I'll get on it.
听着  关于昨晚...
Hey, listen. About last night...
你是说你亲了我那事吗
You mean when you kissed me?
别想太多
You don't have to be weird about it.
要是我愿意想太多呢
Well, what if I want to be weird about it?
有一个猫王的模仿者
Anyway, there's an Elvis impersonator
今晚在930俱乐部有演出
later tonight at the Nine Thirty club.
你想去吗
You want to go?
你怎么知道我喜欢猫王的
How did you know I like Elvis?
政敌调研有时也是挺有用的
Well, opposition research comes in handy sometimes.
赛斯告诉你的吗
Seth told you?
赛斯告诉我的
Seth told me.
我去
I'm in.
好的
All right.
总统要见我
The President wants to see me.
我没收到信息
I didn't get a message.
那就肯定不是什么重要的事了
Well, then it can't be anything too important.
是的
Yeah.
我接下来跟你说的这些事不能让别人知道
What I'm about to tell you has to stay in this room.
-听明白了吗  -是的
- Do you understand? - Of course.
昨天我收到了一份国防部的高度机密文件
Yesterday I received a highly classified DOD file
里面详细描述了如何炸毁国会大厦
detailing how to blow up the Capitol.
我相信艾尔萨卡就是利用这份文件
I believe it's what Al-Sakar used
计划并实施了袭击
to plan and carry out the attack.
我还认为这份文件是通过
I also think the file was given to them
里士满政府里的人流出的
by someone in Richmond's administration.
所以我让你来处理这件事
That's why I had to bring you in on this.
不仅是因为我非常信任你
Not only do I trust you implicitly,
而且这份发布时你还不在这里
you weren't here when the file was being circulated.
谁在
Who was?
这是目前我所了解到的
This is what I managed to put together so far.
亚伦·肖尔
亚伦也在名单上
Aaron's on this list.
我知道  我得避开那些
I know. I had to put down everyone's name
有足够安全等级
who had security clearance
知道这份文件存在的人
that would allow them to know the file even existed.
艾米丽  我觉得白宫里有内鬼
Emily, I think there's a traitor in the White House,
我需要你来帮我找出这个人
and I need you to help me find out who it is.
谢莉
Yeah, Shelly.
纳萨尔死去已经六天了
Nassar's been dead for six days.
我们什么时候能得到答复
When can we expect an answer?
我之前说过了  谢莉
As I said before, Shelly,
我仍然没有获得有关这件事的消息
I still don't have any information about this.
拜托  难道没人想问我有关就职仪式的事吗
Come on, guys, who's gonna ask me about the swearing-in ceremony?
这边  赛斯  赛斯
Over here. Seth. Seth.
纳塔利
Natalie.
关于在国会旧址举行就职仪式的决定
About the decision to hold the swearing-in at the Capitol site --
是如何做出的
how exactly was that reached?
谢谢你  纳塔利
Thank you, Natalie.
自从1800年托马斯·杰斐逊的就职典礼后
So, since Thomas Jefferson's inauguration in 1800,
就职仪式就一直在国会举行
swearing-in ceremonies have been held at the Capitol,
总统认为这有象征性并且有必要
and the President felt it was both symbolic and necessary
继续这种传统  好吧
to continue with that tradition, all right?
我目前就掌握这些消息了
That's actually all I have right now.
我过几个小时再通知你们过来
I am gonna be calling you back in, in a few hours.
谢谢
Thank you.
联络员有没有发来最新的
Have OP send us an updated list
受邀参加就职仪式的人员名单
of who they've invited to the swearing-in.
赛斯
Seth.
聊两句
A word?
谢谢  各位  我一会找你们
Thanks, guys. I'll catch up to you.
丽萨  你好
Lisa. Hey.
你一次都没有叫我
You didn't call on me once.
抱歉  我没看到你
Oh, sorry. I didn't see you.
我已经很明显了
I couldn't have been more clear
就差拿一根
if I had one of those light sticks
指挥飞机的荧光棒了
they use to direct airplanes.
如果这是因为你对
Now, if this is about you
李奥·柯克曼那事还对我有不满的话
holding a grudge about the Leo Kirkman story --
时间有限
Look, there's limited time.
我不可能回答所有人的问题
You know, I can't get to everyone's question,
不过如果你有很紧急的事
but if you have something that's pressing,
你可以给我发邮件
you can always send me an e-mail
-或者联系我办公室的人员  -赛斯
- or reach out to one of the deputies in my office. - Seth.
好吧  我理解
Okay, I get it.
我辜负了你的信任
I betrayed your trust.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
可我的工作就是提出问题
But it's my job to ask questions
而你的工作就是回答问题
and your job to answer them.
总统都原谅我了  你怎么就不能呢
The President can forgive me. Why can't you?
亚伦·肖尔
艾米丽
Emily.
我在到处找你
I was looking all over for you.
你不是要跟我一起
I thought you were gonna sit in
参加讨论议会事项的会议吗
on that legislative affairs meeting with me.
抱歉  我有事要忙
Oh, sorry. I got tied up.
-总统找你什么事  -没什么
- So, what did the President want to see you about? - Nothing.
他只是让我再审查一下
Uh, he just -- he wanted me to take another look
布鲁斯·兰格尔任住房和城市发展部部长的事
at Bruce Rangell for HUD Secretary.
-这事显然对他来说很重要  -是的
- That one's obviously important for him, so... - Yeah.
那今晚来这里接你  八点四十五
Hey, so, tonight, pick you up here -- 8:45?
我觉得我会很忙的
Look, I think I'm gonna be pretty swamped here,
所以还是下次吧
so I'm gonna have to take a rain check.
对不起
I'm sorry.
好吧  下次
Okay. All right. Rain check.
艾米丽  你  你不会
Em -- Emily, listen, you -- you don't --
你不会是对昨晚的事后悔了吧
you don't regret last night, do you?
不是  我只是今晚太忙了
No, I just can't do it tonight.
好吧
Okay.
7号信号系统  SS7
Okay, Signaling System 7 -- SS-7.
可以让每个手机基站互联
lets every cellphone tower talk to each other
这样你的手机到哪里都能用
so your phone works anywhere in the world.
这对我们有什么帮助
How does that help us?
如果我能进入这个系统
If I can get in,
我们可以把你的手机和给你打电话的
we can connect the dots from your cell
神秘女人的手机进行点对点连接
back to the one that mystery woman called you from.
搞定了  我连上了
Got it. I'm in.
-干得好  恰克  -别急着谢我
- Good job, Chuck. - Don't thank me yet.
我还要追踪给打给你的电话的号码
I still got to backtrack the number that called your cell.
DNS反向追踪被发现
-见鬼  -怎么了
- Damn it. - What?
入侵被发现了
Network picked up the intrusion.
只能看谁更快了
It's a race to see what happens first --
是我先追踪到神秘来电的电话
I track your mystery caller's phone,
还是他们先发现我们
or they track us.
快  快
Come on. Come on.
DNS反向追踪被发现
找到了
Got it.
看来是用一个一次性电话拨打的
Looks like the call to your cell came from a burner phone.
从哪里买的
Purchased from where?
里格斯广场  西北方向
杜邦广场上的一家便利店里
A convenience store in Dupont Circle.
-先生  霍斯拉滕议长来了  -谢谢
- Speaker Hookstraten's here, sir. - Thank you, Wyatt.
总统先生  有什么事吗
You wanted to speak with me, Mr. President?
是的  议长女士
Yes, Madam Speaker.
我听说你想和委员会的成员们分享
I was told that you had information on Congressman MacLeish
有关麦克利什议员的消息
that you wanted to share with the committee.
烦请告知我细节
I'm sorry, but I need to know what that was.
六周前一位联邦调查局探员找到我
Six weeks ago, an FBI agent approached me.
她想拿到国会大厦的图纸
She wanted access to the blueprints of the Capitol.
昨天她跟我说
Yesterday, she told me
她有证据指证彼得·麦克利什
she had evidence against Peter MacLeish.
此后她就消失了
And then she never showed up.
那位探员叫什么名字
She -- What was the agent's name?
汉娜·威尔士
Hannah Wells.
麦克利什议员跟我说
Congressman MacLeish told me --
他究竟说了什么来着
what did he say, exactly?
他认为她紧盯着他不放
He thought that she was obsessed with him,
对他的调查太过主观
that her investigation had somehow turned personal.
她也是那样对你的吗
Did she come across that way to you?
完全没有  先生
No, sir, not at all.
你知道她现在在哪吗
Do you know where she is now?
很奇怪  从那时起她就人间蒸发了
Well, strangely, I haven't heard from her since.
好的  谢谢你
Okay, thank you.
金布尔
Kimble...
她为什么想要国会大厦的图纸
why does she want the blueprints for the Capitol Building?
因为这是爆炸案调查中的一部分
She requested them as part of the investigation into the bombing.
没错
Right.
当然  是的
Of course, right.
谢谢
Thank you.
有什么问题吗  总统先生
Is everything all right, sir?
我也不知道
I'm not sure yet.
有什么消息第一时间通知你
I'll let you know as soon as I can.
然后你的保卫会送你到天文台一号楼
Then your detail will bring you back to One Observatory Circle.
天文台一号楼是美国副总统住的地方
我温馨的家
Home, sweet home.
抱歉  打扰了
I'm sorry for the interruption.
完全没有  总统先生
Mr. President. Not at all.
我们正在核对最后的细节
We're just going through some of the final details.
彼得  希望可以一鸣惊人
It's gonna be a great event, Peter.
迈克  请你出来一下
Mike, can I borrow you for a second, please?
借过一下
Excuse me.
我需要和一位叫汉娜·威尔士的联邦探员谈谈
I need to speak with an FBI agent named Hannah Wells.
-能帮我找到她吗  -好的先生
- Can you find her for me? - Yes, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
汉娜·威尔士
Hannah Wells?
为什么总统想见汉娜·威尔士
Why does the president want to know about Hannah Wells?
她对彼得·麦克利什的调查
He's interested in some information
引起了他的兴趣
she claims to have on Peter MacLeish.
为什么  她声称自己手里有什么消息吗
Why? What kind of information did she say she had?
她没有
She didn't.
这也正是我一直想搞清楚的事
That's, um -- that's what I'm trying to figure out.
你知道在哪里能找到她吗
Do you know where I could find her?
我不知道
I wish I did.
她昨天在15街和K街的交叉口出了车祸
She totaled her car yesterday at 15th and "K"
然后逃走了
and fled the scene.
我检查了当地的每一家医院
I've checked every local hospital,
甚至尝试定位她的手机
even tried pinging her phone.
你是说一位联邦调查员就这样凭空消失了
You're saying an FBI agent just up and disappeared?
是的
Yes.
谁知道杰森·阿特伍德
I mean, who knows what kind of mess
让她卷入了什么事情之中
Jason Atwood's got her mixed up in,
你想了解更多威尔士探员的信息吗
but you want to know more about Agent Wells?
这是她的档案
Here's her file.
自己看吧
See for yourself.
谢谢
Thanks.
你好  我是威尔士探员
Hi. I'm Agent Wells.
我之前打电话想看一下你的监控录像
I called earlier about looking at your surveillance footage.
当然  没问题
Yes, of course.
在后面
Uh, it's in the back.
鲍勃  帮我看一下店
Bob, can you take the register?
-好的  -这边请
- No problem. - Right this way.
-非常感谢  -不客气
- Thanks for doing this. - Yeah.
请你调出1月26日下午
Can you pull up some footage from January 26th,
3点32分左右的监控录像
around 3:32 p.M.?
电话是在那个时候开始启用的
That's when the phone was initiated.
停
Stop.
你有外部监控摄像头吗
Do you have any exterior cameras?
在停车场里有的
Yeah, in the parking lot.
好的  调一下那个摄像头
Okay, I need you to pull that up.
停
Freeze.
放大
And zoom in.
我是恰克
This is Chuck.
恰克  我需要你查一块车牌
Hey, Chuck, I need you to run a plate for me.
在宣誓就职仪式上
At the swearing-in,
这份文件会由威廉·赛兹摩尔上校带来
the invocation will be delivered by a Colonel William Sizemore,
他曾是参议员所在部队的牧师
he was the congressman's Army pastor,
而且他会用从老家俄勒冈带来的
and he'll be sworn in using Beth MacLeish's Bible,
贝丝·麦克利什的圣经进行宣誓仪式
which is being brought in from the family home in Oregon.
丽萨
Yeah, Lisa.
谢谢
Thank you,
我刚刚收到线报
I've just learned from a source
马吉德·纳萨尔谋杀案的嫌疑人
that a suspect is in custody
已经被关押了
in connection with the murder of Majid Nassar,
白宫对此有何回应
what is the White House's response
还有  我们什么时候可以
and -- and when can we expect
获知嫌犯的身份
to learn more about the suspect's identity.
丽萨  我得打断你一下
Lisa, let me interrupt you right there,
白宫评论一场正在进行的调查
as it would be inappropriate for the White House to comment
是十分不合适的,
on an ongoing investigation
显而易见
now, that being said,
这个事件十分重要
this is obviously a matter of extreme importance --
白宫知道多久了
How long has the White House known?
我们什么时候能知道他的名字
When can we find out their name?
你担心公众对总统的信心吗
Are you worried about the public's confidence in the president?
白宫还隐藏了什么
What else is the White House hiding?
剩下的问题会交由
I would direct any remaining questions you have
军事犯罪调查员回答
to the Army criminal investigators, okay?
我现在只能回答这么多
That's all I have for right now, guys,
国会宣誓仪式的时候再见
I'll see you at the Capitol for the swearing-in.
你不能就这样一走了之
You can't just walk away from this,
我们和公众都有权知道答案
we deserve answers, the public deserves answers!
很少有白宫西翼人员来这里
Don't get many West Wingers here,
尤其是总统的资深助理
especially senior aides to POTUS.
这是件特殊的任务
It's a special assignment.
所有从白宫打出的电话都有记录  是吗
Now, all phone calls from the White House are catalogued, correct?
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am,
所有的信件  电话  通信情况
every letter, call, correspondence --
-都保留了历史纪录  -太好了
- all preserved for history. - Perfect,
我想找出是谁
I'm trying to find who, from the White House,
在2015年6月23号
contacted the Secretary of Defense
8点到8点33分从白宫
on June 23, 2015,
打电话给国防部
between 8:00 and 8:33 A.M.
小菜一碟  稍等一下
Shouldn't be a problem, just give me a sec.
好了
Here you go,
2015年6月23号8点23分
there was a call logged
有一通打给
to the Office of the Secretary of Defense --
国防部办公室的电话
23 A.M., 23, June 2015.
是谁打的
Who made the call?
白宫幕僚长查尔斯·兰登
White House Chief of Staff Charles Langdon.
查尔斯·兰登  幕僚长
有关于威尔士探员的新消息吗
Do we have an update on Agent Wells?
她昨天在15街和K街交界处出了车祸
She was in a car accident yesterday at 15th and "K",
据目击者说  她离开了车祸现场
and according to witnesses, she abandoned the scene,
联调局还没能找到她的下落
FBI hasn't been able to track her down.
等下
Wait a second,
她在来提交有关麦克利什议员的
she was in a car accident on her way
信息时出的车祸
to provide information on Congressman MacLeish?
这有点太巧合了吧
that's a bit of a coincidence.
福斯特主任让我看了看她的档案
Director Foerstel gave me a look at her file,
撇开优点不谈
merits of accommodation aside,
威尔士探员在经历一段很痛苦的日子
Agent Wells has been going through a difficult time,
根据亚特伍德自己的笔记
according to Atwood's own notes,
-他觉得她的判断力受到了影响  -为什么
- he felt her judgment might be compromised. - Why?
她和在国会爆炸中死去的
She was in a relationship with someone that died at the Capitol,
斯科特·惠勒议员有一段感情
Senator Scott Wheeler.
我只知道她在我们知道这份文件前
All I know is that she went to Hookstraten
就去找霍斯拉滕
looking for the blueprints for the Capitol Building
要国会大厦的蓝图了
weeks before we knew about the file,
所以她要么像其他人说的那样疯了
so she's either crazy, like everybody says
要么她真的知道点什么
or she knows something,
我们得继续找她
we got to keep looking for her.
好的  长官
Yes, sir.
联调局  不许动
FBI! Stop right there!
转过来
Turn around,
转身
turn around.
我认识你
I know you,
你是查尔斯·兰登
you're Charles Langdon,
你是里士满总统的幕僚长
you were Richmond's Chief of Staff,
大家都以为你死了
everyone thinks you're dead.
你得赶快离开这里
You've got to get out of here,
你可能被跟踪了
they could have followed you.
是你告诉我麦克利什信息的吗
You're the one calling me about MacLeish?
你不知道躲避他们有多难
You don't know how hard it is to stay hidden from them.
那是个女人的声音
It was a woman's voice.
他们永远不会停止找我
They're never gonna stop searching for me.
"他们"是谁  这一切背后是谁
Who's "They"? Who is behind this?
他们为什么要留麦克利什活下来
Why do they keep MacLeish alive?
这  这超乎你的想象
It's -- It's bigger than you think,
不要相信任何人
don't trust anyone.
趴下
Get down!
我是拉辛克
This is Russink.
恰克
Hey, Chuck,
我拿到一个门禁卡
I got - a security key card here,
上面有一个标志
it's, uh, got a logo on it,
字母"M"  外面有个圆圈
it's an "M" - with a circle around it.
"M"
"M"? Um...
可能是弗吉尼亚州高端私人安监公司
Could be Metway Security out of Virginia --
里面的迈特威安保团队
super high-end private security and monitoring firm,
一两年前他们想招我
they offer me a job every year or two.
我把背面的序列号告诉你
All right, I'm gonna give you the serial number on the back,
帮我查查看是用来打开什么的
run it for me, see what this unlocks,
-准备好了吗  -说吧
- okay, you ready? - Yeah, shoot.
ZT3267E
Zulu-Tango-3-2-6-7-Echo.
汉娜
Hannah?
汉娜  你还在吗
Hannah, you still there?
找到有用的消息后打给我
Call me when you got something.
说到这个记者  丽萨·乔丹
All right, so this reporter, Lisa Jordan,
她知道我们拘留了个人
she knows we have someone in custody.
她只是不知道那人是亚特伍德
She just doesn't know that it's Atwood?
没错  她知道我们逮捕了一个人
That's right. She knows we've arrested someone.
她只是不知道是谁
She just doesn't know who it is.
那她什么把柄也没有
Then, she has nothing.
她知道我们有所隐瞒
She knows we're hiding something.
总统先生  我们已同意在真相大白之前
Mr. President, we agreed not to tell the press anything
对媒体封锁消息
until we have all the facts.
我们已经知道真相了
Well, we have them now.
联调局刚刚上交了他们的报告
The FBI just handed in their report,
杰森·亚特伍德确实杀了马吉德·纳萨尔
and it concludes that Jason Atwood did, indeed, kill Majid Nassar.
这不可能
That's incredible.
我请乔丹女士留下来做白宫通讯记者
I asked Ms. Jordan to stay on as a White House correspondent
以督促我们保持诚实
to keep us honest.
她谨守了她的诺言
She kept up her end of the bargain.
我们也该这样做
We need to do the same.
告诉她我们会给她一个独家新闻
Tell her we'll give her an exclusive
关于我们拘留的人
on the man that we have in custody,
但她得等到明天了
but she's gonna have to wait till tomorrow.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
长官  我对亚特伍德的事很遗憾
Sir, I'm sorry about Atwood.
我知道你不希望这是真的
I know you didn't want it to be true.
大家都不希望
None of us did.
长官  我在想
Oh, sir, I was thinking if, uh...
你是否会重新考虑
if-if you're having second thoughts
任命布鲁斯·兰格尔为住房及城市发展部部长
on Bruce Rangell for Secretary of Housing,
我可以随时调查他的信息
I could always pull up more information on him to look over.
我对兰格尔很放心
I'm not having second thoughts on Rangell.
你怎么会有这个念头
What would make you think that?
对不起
I-I'm sorry.
我一定是
I-I must have been, um,
我一定是胡思乱想了
I must have been thinking about something else.
车队将在三十分钟后出发前往国会大厦
The motorcade leaves for the Capitol in 30 minutes.
-谢谢你  -长官
- Thank you. - Sir.
里特
Ritter.
里特探员  我是约翰·福斯特
Agent Ritter, it's John Foerstel.
我能为你做些什么
What can I do for you?
你之前让我随时上报汉娜·威尔士的情况
You asked me to keep the White House in the loop on Hannah Wells.
我刚接到从弗吉尼亚州的一个令人不安的电话
I just got a disturbing phone call out of Virginia.
威尔士探员射杀了一个人
Agent Wells shot someone?
是的  长官
Yes, sir,
在弗雷德里克斯堡的一个农场上
at a farm in Fredericksburg.
联调局还在调查尸体身份
The FBI's still working to identify the body,
但几个目击者称
but witnesses claim
他们看到了一个和威尔士探员很像的人
they saw someone fitting Agent Wells' description
与死者交火  之后逃离现场
engaged in a shootout before fleeing the scene.
到底发生了什么
What the hell is going on?
联调局正在华盛顿开展全面追捕
The Feds are throwing a net over D.C.,
他们的电子作战中心监控着
and their EOC is monitoring every camera and feed
方圆48公里内的所有摄像头信号
within a 30-mile radius.
我会确保我们的人
I'll make sure our people
也在提防她
are on the lookout for her, as well.
怎么  你认为她是个威胁
What, you think she's a threat?
我也不清楚  长官
I don't know, sir.
但在过去的二十四小时内
But I can't logically explain her actions
她的行为解释不通
over the past 24 hours.
麦克利什和福斯特
We should consider that both MacLeish
对她的看法可能是对的
and Foerstel might be right about her.
宁可反应过度  冤枉了她
And I'd rather we overreact and be wrong
也不该低估形势  事后悔不当初
than underestimate her and live to regret it.
好吧  谢谢你  迈克
Okay, thanks, Mike.
嗨  恰克
Hey, Chuck.
汉娜  我一直在监控警方的搜索
Hannah, I've been monitoring the police scanners,
市局警察  联调局  他们都在找你
Metro Police, the Bureau, they're all looking for you.
我不知道我还能帮你多久
I don't know how much longer I can help you.
没事  我明白
Look, I understand.
门禁卡有没有线索
Were you able to find out anything about the key card?
有
Yeah.
它能打开路易斯安娜电力通讯公司大楼
It gives you access to room 7 on the 8th floor
八楼的七号房间
of the PLC Building on Louisiana.
路易斯安娜
Louisiana?
恰克  七号房间是朝东还是朝西
Chuck, room 7 -- - does it face east or west?
朝东  怎么了
East. Why?
能看到国会大厦的台阶
You can see the steps.
汉娜  你在想什么了
Hannah, what are you thinking?
距离国会大厦很近
Proximity to the Capitol,
可以直接瞄准讲台
direct line of sight to the platform.
恰克  他们要杀柯克曼
Chuck, they're gonna kill Kirkman.
一切都会好起来的
It'll be okay.
我只希望在做出无法挽回的决定之前
I just wish we had more time to figure everything out
能有时间把事情查清楚
before we did something so permanent.
汤姆  如果你这样想
Tom, if you feel that way,
那我们就不应该举办这个仪式
then we should not go through with this.
我们没有别的选择
We don't have a choice.
我们有的唯一证据还是间接的
The only evidence we have is circumstantial.
可能是我们错了
We could be wrong.
这个国家承受不了另一场打击了
The country can't afford another setback.
彼得
Peter.
所有人都在等着  该出发了
Everyone's waiting. It's time to leave.
出了什么事
What's wrong?
我们十分钟前就该在车里了
We were supposed to be in the car 10 minutes ago.
我觉得我无法坚持到底了
I don't know if I can go through with this.
宝贝  你当然可以
Honey, of course you can.
不  我觉得我们该重新考虑一下
No. I think we need to rethink this thing.
临阵畏缩再正常不过了
It is perfectly normal to have cold feet,
但今天对我们来说至关重要
but this is a great day for all of us.
这恰恰是我们一直以来奋斗的目标
It is exactly what we've been working for.
是的
Yeah.
但牺牲了多少呢
But at what cost?
只要值得  无论代价
At any cost necessary.
彼得  选中你幸存下来是有原因的
Peter, you were chosen to survive for a reason.
你肩负着一项重大的责任
You've been given a tremendous responsibility
让这个国家涅槃重生
to restore this nation
能够再一次成为以前的那个帝国
to the empire it once was and can be again.
我们的朋友对你很有信心
Our friends placed their faith in you.
如果他们见了你这个样子会怎么想
What would they think if they saw you like this?
你现在站在风口浪尖  彼得
You are on the cusp, Peter.
现在不是软弱的时候
This isn't the time for weakness.
答应我你会坚持下去
Now tell me you agree.
答应我  彼得
Tell me you agree, Peter.
好吧
Okay.
很好
Good.
那我们走吧
Now let's go.
丽萨
Lisa.
不好意思  科迪
Excuse me, Cody.
我把你的问题转告了总统
I took your question to the president.
让我猜猜看  无可奉告
Let me guess, no comment.
如果我说了算  实话说
If it was up to me, honestly,
没错  无可奉告
yeah, no comment.
这件事我们一直太过被动
We've been way too reactive around here,
以后情况会改观的
and that's gonna change,
但总统欣赏你
but the president appreciates you,
所以我们决定给你
and we've decided to grant you
纳萨尔调查的独家新闻
the exclusive on the Nassar investigation.
真的吗
Really?
-什么时候  -很快
- When? - Soon.
现在我们先让美国庆祝一番
For now, let's let America celebrate.
我会保持联系
I'll be in touch.
八楼安全
8th floor, all clear.
安全
Clear.
尊敬的女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
有请美国总统
the President of the United States.
我想在开始之前占用一点时间
I wanted to take a moment before we get started
恭喜你即将成为副总统
and congratulate you on becoming vice president.
我们的祖国距离复兴还有很长的路要走
Our country's got a long road to recovery,
但现在这是个很大的进步
but this is another big step.
谢谢  长官  我不会让你失望的
Thank you, sir. I won't let you down.
艾米丽·罗迪斯
Emily Rhodes.
罗迪斯女士  我是接线总机处的阿曼达
Ms. Rhodes, it's Amanda at the switchboard.
-你好  -你之前叫我深入调查一下
- Yes. - You asked me to look deeper
查尔斯·兰登在六月二十三号的通话记录
into Charles Langdon's phone records June 23.
结果是
Uh, as it turns out,
他那天不在办公室
he wasn't in his office that day.
什么
I'm sorry?
我再次确认了他的行程安排
I double-checked his schedule.
兰登先生在前往日内瓦的跨洋旅程中
Uh, Mr. Langdon was on an overseas trip to Geneva.
那谁给五角大楼打的电话
Then who made the call to the Pentagon?
他的副手  亚伦·肖尔
His deputy, Aaron Shore.
谢谢你
Thank you.
总统先生  是时候了
Mr. President, it's time.
尊敬的女士们先生们  请就坐
Ladies and gentlemen, please be seated.
下午好
Good afternoon.
当我看到你们这么多人
When I see how many of you
风雨无阻地来一起见证
have chosen to brave the elements
这个重要而特殊的时刻
to mark this momentous occasion,
我只想说我备受鼓舞
I can only tell you how inspired I am.
今日  我站在
Today, I stand...
美国最惨烈的悲剧留下的遗址之上
...on the site of one of America's greatest tragedies
承诺大家国家将要重生
and offer the promise of America's rebirth.
我宣誓成为美国总统的那夜
The night I was sworn in as President of the United States,
这个国家
this nation,
我们的祖国
our nation,
笼罩在混乱之中
was in the grips of chaos.
但是现在放眼望去  国会大厦面前
But now, as I look out on the Mall,
我看不到任何一个畏缩不前的人
I don't see a people that were scared.
看不到任何一张恐惧的面孔
I don't see a people that were frightened.
-不好意思  -我看到的是我们如此坚强
- Excuse me. - I see that we are strong...
不好意思
Excuse me.
我们如此骄傲
...and that we are proud
我们又一次如此团结
and that we are, once again, united.
愿主保佑你们所有人
God bless all of you
愿主保佑美利坚众合国
and these United States of America.
尊敬的女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我无比光荣地向你们介绍
it is my profound honor to introduce
彼得·麦克利什议员  我们新的副总统
Congressman Peter MacLeish, our next vice president.
-恭喜  -谢谢  长官
- Congratulations. - Thank you, sir.
麦克利什议员
Congressman MacLeish,
请你把手放在圣经之上
if you'll place your hand on the Bible
跟我重复
and repeat after me.
"我  彼得·路易斯·麦克利什"
"I, Peter Lewis MacLeish..."
我  彼得·路易斯·麦克利什
I, Peter Lewis MacLeish...
"谨庄严宣誓  我决心维护和捍卫
"...do solemnly swear to support and defend
合众国宪法"
the Constitution of the United States..."
谨庄严宣誓  我决心维护和捍卫
...do solemnly swear to support and defend
合众国宪法
the Constitution of the United States...
"防止被国内外一切敌人侵犯"
"...against all enemies, foreign and domestic..."
防止被国内外一切敌人侵犯
...against all enemies, foreign and domestic...
不好意思  请让一下
Excuse me. Excuse me.
"我将忠于宪法  恪守不渝"
"...that I bear true faith and allegiance to the same..."
我将忠于宪法  恪守不渝
...that I bear true faith and allegiance to the same...
不好意思  让一下
Excuse me. Move!
"我自愿承担这项义务
"...and that I take this obligation freely,
毫无保留之意  也决无推诿之心"
without any mental reservation or purpose of evasion."
我自愿承担这项义务
...and that I take this obligation freely,
毫无保留之意  也决无推诿之心
without any mental reservation or purpose of evasion,
我必忠勤尽责
and that I will well and faithfully
为执行我即将承担的职务
discharge the duties of the office
鞠躬尽瘁
on which I am about to enter.
"愿主助我"
"So help me God."
愿主助我
So help me God.
我看到一个嫌疑犯
I have a suspect in my line of sight.
我需要一个小队支援
I need a team.
恭喜你  副总统先生
Congratulations, Mr. Vice President.
■
扫描二维码
关注凤凰八卦
枪  小心枪
Gun! Gun!